## **Edison Tang Lim**

edisontanglim@yahoo.com | +1-408-797-8162

#### **SUMMARY**

Senior Product Manager and strategic Technology Innovation Leader with rotational experience in consulting, architecture, project management, methodology, and hands-on development roles in the United States, Philippines, Canada, Germany, and America. Excellent track record and broad exposure to diverse initiative types, including business transformation, merger and acquisition, legacy system replacement, quality improvement, and organization capability building

Recognized area expert with presentations in international and regional conferences. Consistent top-rated performer and a strong team leader who helps teams to succeed

Grew up in Taiwan and the Philippines; speak speaks fluent English, Mandarin Chinese, and Tagalog

#### SKILLS AND CERTIFICATIONS

SAP: SAP Order-to-Cash, Materials Management, Fiori, Workflow, BRFplus, Personas, ALE, Solution Manager, HANA Cloud Platform, ECATT, ABAP

Integration architecture: ORTEC Load Building, JDA TMS, RedPrairie (JDA) WMS, Terra Forecasting, Accenture CAS, SAP-to-SAP global supply chain integration

Other: Supply chain, Consumer Packaged Goods, design thinking, Java, JavaScript, HTML5, R, design patterns

Certifications: Lean Six Sigma Green Belt, SAP Certified Application Associate - Order Fulfillment with SAP ERP 6.0 EHP5, ITIL V3 Foundation

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Hewlett-Packard Company – Cincinnati, OH, USA; Toronto, ON, Canada

January 2004 – Present

Senior SAP Product Manager / Technology and Innovation Team Lead for P&G (July 2009 – Present)

Responsibilities: Member of Global Supply Chain Template Design Council; define product vision, strategy, architecture and roadmap; oversee successful product development; research industry trends, develop business case, and drive portfolio decisions; lead technical and quality decisions across products

- Directed product development across more than 50 global and regional SAP implementation projects, including some of P&G's (and industry's) largest SAP implementation projects
- Oversaw production solution health and problem management; reduced problem records by 20%
- Co-innovated with external product partners
- Started the SAP New Idea Team that delivered 30+ innovation initiatives
- Led SAP development transformation that created a new technical framework, design paradigm, and development methodology. The effort saved P&G more than \$1.5 million in the first year
- Authored company-wide solution quality policies used across IT service vendors
- Set up the Solution Quality Network that linked product, operation, and development organizations The network drove early resolution to 700+ defects in 6 product areas in the first 6 months
- Presented solutions at industry conferences
- Mentored team members (including junior product managers); trained 200+ technical specialists

## Strategy Management Office Lead, HP Enterprise SAP Supply Chain Practice (April 2015 – Present)

Responsibilities: Provide leadership and give direction to the newly established Strategy Management Office of HP Enterprise SAP Supply Chain Practice

- Research state-of-the-business, perform competitive analyses, and advice practice direction and business model
- Set up processes and procedures to ensure smooth functioning of the office
- Remove roadblocks; create excitements, accountability, and reward system for innovation

## Project Manager / Methodology Champion for P&G (January 2007 – January 2010)

Responsibilities: Lead SAP implementation projects; roll-out project implementation methodology to all project teams

- Led teams of up to 60 direct global team members through 3 full SAP project implementations
- Piloted automated testing that reduced testing time by 60%
- Led HP technical training initiative; trained more than 200+ technology consultants
- Co-designed and rolled out the new standardized SAP project implementation methodology

## SAP Integration Architect / Technical Project Manager for P&G (October 2005 – March 2007)

Responsibilities: Align supply chain integration needs, priorities, and implementation approach with global business and IT leaders; architect P&G-Gillette global supply chain integration solution; lead technical project implementation

- Designed huge supply chain integration architecture that supported over \$1 billion in synergy savings
- Aligned business and IT integration approach to manageable scope and timeline
- Led global technical team of more than 40 members in delivering the productized Gillette Integration Solution; it became P&G's global standard for integrating internal and external supply chain systems

## SAP Sales and Distribution Implementation Lead for P&G (January 2004 – December 2005)

Responsibilities: Lead implementation teams through 2 full SAP implementation projects

- Created solutions that automated P&G's high volume, high velocity order management processes; the solutions became P&G's globally most important sales and distribution productivity solution
- Replaced legacy shipping and transportation solutions used in more than 50 North America plants

#### Procter & Gamble Company – Philippines; Germany; USA

June 2002 – December 2003

#### SAP Sales and Distribution Systems Analyst (June 2002 – December 2003)

Responsibilities: Analyze sales and distribution processes; design, configure, and develop sales and distribution solutions; participate in SAP technology implementation projects

• Supported 4 SAP implementation projects; trained approximately 60 users and team members

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of California, Berkeley, Haas School of Business – Berkeley, USA

August 2015 – Current

Master of Business Administration (MBA), EWMBA Program – Class of 2018

#### De La Salle University – Manila, Philippines

June 1998 – August 2002

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, Major in Software Technology

- Summa Cum Laude
- Vice President of Academic Affairs, La Salle Computer Society

#### Technology and Business Massive Open Online Courses – Online

2013 - Current